Hi, everyone!
Cloud 2024.2 has been officially released!
Come and check out this new feature!
Updating your Cloud!
Upgrading with us!
New features such as GPU simulation, secondary modeling, and virtual model chest adjustment
will be fully enhanced with the brand-new Doku window!
This video will be a demonstration of the whole process of clothing development,
helping you to connect to new application scenarios.
Let's take a look at the features you've been looking forward to!
First, it's the update related to the user interface.
Cloud interface now supports dark and light colors, two color themes.
You can switch between the main menu, settings, user settings, and user interface options.
Select light color, restart the software, and switch to light color theme mode.
You can now set it according to your preferences.
In addition, it also adjusts the UI content displayed in the property editor after selecting the version.
The material, the thinning layer, and the position of the shape optimization
have been changed from the previous bottom to the position above,
and a new multi-component layer has been added,
which will increase the thickness of the rendering and the curve of the edges.
A new direction option has been added,
which will make it easy to connect to the ArrayWare style settings and some special application scenarios.
In the 2024.2 version, we have made major updates to the ArrayWare window.
The updated ArrayWare can make it more intuitive and convenient for everyone to call for 3D assets.
First, we can find the new ArrayWare switch button under the original ArrayWare window.
Click on Try Now to open the new ArrayWare.
A new ArrayWare icon will appear in the upper right corner.
Click on the icon to open and close the new ArrayWare window.
You can also click on the button in the lower left corner to return to the old version of the ArrayWare window.
In the new ArrayWare window, assets will be classified into five categories,
clothing, virtual models, fabrics, accessories, and scenarios.
Each category includes the default CLO assets and community assets from Connect.
You can choose to download the assets you want or all assets.
Choose the fabric.
In the side of the fabric page, select the paper file folder.
You can also directly click on the paper file folder to enter.
In the paper file window, the top position will display the path, convenient positioning, and return to the upper file folder.
When we select the material, we can open the display preview.
You can see the material in a more clear and intuitive way.
You can also display the material in the same way as before.
Switch to clothing, community assets.
You can see a lot of online 3D clothing assets.
Here is the free content.
You can directly download it after logging into the Connect account.
In addition, the materials purchased by the account can be viewed and downloaded and used in the purchase option card on the left side.
Now we can create a dedicated, multi-selected, self-defined drawing library.
All you need to do is click on the plus button at the top,
select the file folder you want to add, and you can create my drawing library.
You can also add multiple different file folders to the left side of the page.
If you need to manage a lot of 3D assets,
you can create a new, self-defined drawing library to manage it more freely.
Finally, switch to the second option card at the top.
After logging into the Closet account, you can browse the files in the current account.
The section content on the left side is consistent with the Closet page.
It is convenient for everyone to quickly find the files they want.
Then we will load this shirt with double click.
Now we will use this shirt to show you how to use the Closet app.
Let's take a look at the Closet app.
First of all, I will introduce two function optimizations related to blockization.
First of all, when the customized clothing block is opened again,
you can sew it by clicking on the cutout.
When everyone is making clothes,
it is usually necessary to sew according to the cutout.
For example, the bubble sleeve in this style.
You can see that the cutout on the large sleeve sleeve and the sleeve on the sleeve is well sewn.
Now we define the style of this bubble sleeve as the clothing block.
This is an automatic blockization label tool.
For this shirt, the part of the current automatic identification is not complete enough.
At this time, we can choose to edit the part and redefine the front part of the shirt.
The back and sleeve parts are also the same operation.
For the collar part that has been accurately identified,
we can directly choose to save the part and quickly save it.
After defining it, we can self-define it in the user,
find the option to sew by clicking on the cutout in the block.
It is a default selection.
If you cancel the selection and re-load it,
you will see that it is a cutout.
If you click on it and load the clothing block again,
you can see that it is now sewed by clicking on the cutout.
In addition, due to the fact that the parts between the styles
are usually incompatible,
in order to prevent the parts between the styles from being combined,
we can see the default selection of the module combination
to prevent the parts between the styles from being combined.
When we use the parts under the style to combine,
it can be done normally.
But when we switch to other styles to load the parts,
a warning window will appear.
This will effectively prevent the wrong parts from being combined.
Now, when we convert the straight line point to a free curve point,
we can choose to keep the curve rate or tight conversion.
When choosing to keep the curve rate,
we will create multiple curve points to maintain the curve shape.
This function is the same as the previous effect.
When choosing to tight conversion,
we will not create other curve points.
It should be noted that such conversion
may cause the original curve shape to change.
Similarly, when converting the curve point to a straight line point,
we can choose any conversion method according to our needs.
The two modes make the conversion method more flexible and diverse.
In the new version,
we can remove the interlocking relationship between the inner line and the base line on the symmetrical interlocking plate.
For example, on this shirt,
we only need to sew a small label on the left side of the large body,
then we can remove the interlocking on the inner shape on the right front piece,
and then delete it.
The base line is the same.
We first remove the interlocking,
then select the base line,
then remove the interlocking,
then delete the unnecessary base line.
This function is also a long-awaited function for everyone.
I hope everyone can use it when you need it in the future.
Now I want to change the circle of this shirt to a shoulder strap.
At this time, you can use the function of changing the plate.
This time, the replacement plate has also been optimized.
First of all, we can right-click on the plate that needs to be replaced.
Then right-click on the plate that needs to be replaced,
and then select the plate that needs to be replaced.
This makes the replacement operation more convenient.
In addition, we can replace the plate with a number that is not consistent with the original plate.
After selecting the plate that needs to be replaced,
you will see a tool prompt.
We need to select the point that matches,
then press the return key to confirm completion.
You can see that the replacement is completed at this time.
Next, we will modify the button on the shirt skirt.
In this way, you can modify the material of the button on the shirt skirt.
In 2024.2, the metal material for the button has been added to the preset.
You can use it according to your needs and select the preset you need.
This makes your operation more convenient.
This time, we have three updates on the code.
First of all, the new version supports the function of increasing the size of the code on the current code basis.
You can select the smallest size,
right-click to find it,
and insert the size at the top,
to add a smaller size.
In addition, you can use the same method
to add a new size between the two sizes.
In addition, the version also adds the function of adding a code.
You can enter the code.
When you paste the code on the board,
you can see that there is a cross mark on the corresponding position of the 2D window to indicate the location of the code.
When you switch to the edit code tool,
you can select the cross mark to enter the code.
Then we will switch to different sizes to simulate and check their effects separately.
Next, let's take a look at the two functions updated about the measurement points.
First of all, in 2024.2,
we have added the measurement point group function.
You can classify the measurement points through the group,
so that the information of the measurement looks clearer and more flexible.
The group you see now is the front and back of the costume.
You can fold up the measurement point groups that you don't need to see here.
You can also classify and rename according to your own preferences.
When a costume has multiple sizes,
in the new version,
you can hide the sizes that you don't need to see in the measurement point label.
This will make you feel more comfortable
and easier to focus on the current size.
You can also click on the icon again
to open the corresponding size display.
Next, let's take a look at the two functions updated about the arrangement.
First of all, in 2024.2,
when you have selected the size that needs to be arranged,
you can choose to classify each size
and classify the arrangement according to the size.
And when you switch to the machine code,
you can distinguish the current machine code and other sizes more clearly.
In addition,
the current version also simplifies the arrangement of different colors.
The arrangement and the color are linked.
You can click on the color you need to arrange,
and then arrange.
When you switch to the color,
you can see that the colors of the same fabric will be arranged together.
From 2024.2,
you can adjust the chest shape of the virtual model.
In the virtual model editor,
a new editor about the chest is added,
allowing you to create a self-defined chest model.
You can adjust the shape
to make the chest closer to the round chest
or the water-bottomed chest.
When you need to adjust the chest again,
you can click on the reset button in the upper right corner
to reset the current effect.
If the shoulder is pointed towards the female model,
the chest will be bigger and wider.
The shorter the shoulder, the bigger the chest,
the wider the chest, the wider the chest,
and the height is pointed towards the female model.
The position of the breast point is high and low.
You can see this parameter more objectively
through adjustment.
Next, let's take a look at the virtual model joints.
In 2024.2,
the size reduction and hiding function of the joints is supported.
Open the virtual model joint.
In the adjustment window in the upper right corner,
the size adjustment has been added.
You can adjust the size of the joint to the size of your preference.
You can also reset it to the default size.
If you don't need to see a certain joint,
you can hide them in the right-click menu.
You can also right-click to display again.
In addition,
you can see that the current virtual model joint adjustment window
is also different from the previous one.
You can switch between FK and IK modes
directly in the mode area
to display the corresponding editing tool.
In 2024.2,
the function of flattening as a sheet is also optimized.
We can use this function to extract
the chest sheet drawn with a 3D drawing pen.
When you use the flattening as a sheet,
you will see that the sheet
will open the logic of the front and back sheets
in the 2D window.
In addition,
the presentation of the line direction of the sheet will be more reasonable.
After completing the basic production of the chest sheet,
when simulating and adjusting the shoulder strap of the chest,
there will often be a slip of the shoulder strap.
At this time,
we will add a fixing pin on the shoulder strap on one side.
Then,
you can copy the corresponding position of the fixing pin
to the corresponding position on the corresponding sheet
to facilitate the adjustment of the shoulder strap.
In 2024.2,
we optimized the extension function of the stretch bar.
We recommend that you use the stretch bar tool
to add the stretch bar.
At this time,
you can see that different stretch areas
are distinguished by different colors,
and you can see that the arrow
is only the beginning and end of the stretch bar.
Then,
you can see the attribute editor.
The extension below the stretch bar
has been added to the setting of the beginning and end.
You can set different extension effects
according to your needs here
to adjust the position where they end.
When you set the end points corresponding to the two stretch bars
to the stretch bar,
you can find that the two stretch bars do not overlap,
but are connected.
Next,
let's take a look at the function update
about the fabric generator.
Now,
after opening the fabric generator,
the display of the upper fabric preview window is blank
because no fabric has been generated at this time.
After entering the information,
we will select the fabric type,
then select the ingredient.
You will see that the ingredients here can be freely selected,
and the type of ingredient
is also changed according to the type of fabric.
This makes the ingredient setting of the fabric more diverse
and increases freedom.
After selecting the ingredients,
the fabric preview will be displayed on the top.
After completing the setting of the ingredient ratio,
we will add the prepared texture sticker
and apply the fabric.
From the new version,
the color setting moves to the position
where the material content rests on the top,
depending on everyone's choice and setting.
When you want to modify the color of the fabric,
you can use this new function to replace the color.
Next, let's take a look at
the difference between it and the previous version
of the color.
You can see that there are three braids here.
The leftmost is the original braids.
We use the second braids
to show the effect of blocking the color.
Use the third braids
to show the effect of replacing the color.
When using the blocking color
and applying a new color,
you can see that the texture color on the fabric
is completely blocked,
and the texture detail color becomes lighter.
Then let's use this new function
to replace the color,
select the fabric,
and then find it in the attribute editor.
If you find it in the attribute editor,
refresh the color,
replace it,
and then select the color you need,
you can complete the replacement of the texture color.
You can see that in contrast to the fill color,
the replacement color will be clearer
and retain the details of the original texture.
I hope this function
can improve your experience
when changing the color of the clothing.
When there are multiple 3D clothing records in a file,
it is very likely that there will be
indistinguishable situations.
In this update,
we have adjusted the shrinkage of the 3D clothing record.
When you stop the mouse
at the top of the corresponding record,
you will see a bigger and clearer picture.
This can help you
find the record you want
in multiple 3D clothing records.
Next, we will use this handbag
to show the following functions.
The current handbag material type
is a wool product.
There is a new option below,
the difference between the lines.
This function can quickly achieve
the line performance you want
.
When you turn on the irregularity,
you will see that the position of the fabric
is more random.
Slide the slide or enter the value
to adjust the ratio or frequency
of the irregularity of the line.
You can get different line effects.
In addition, when you open the ball,
you can see that the fabric
has increased the effect of the ball.
Slide the slide or enter the value
to adjust the length, thickness
and frequency of the fabric ball
to make the line performance more real and diverse.
In addition,
CLOU has added a new hair vinegar generator.
You can more conveniently adjust the length
and curve of the hair.
Without too much operation,
you can easily show the effect of hair vinegar.
Let's add a new color to this handbag.
Select all properties,
change its material type
to hair,
and delete the texture.
Open the texture and check the hair effect at this time.
Click on the fabric,
you can see that
a new hair vinegar button has been added.
Open the hair vinegar generator,
you can see the default length and curve direction.
Click on the application
and turn on the rendering again.
You can see that
the hair effect is different from before.
Then apply a preset hair material.
Turn on the rendering first to check the effect.
Then open the hair vinegar generator.
We can adjust the parameters
to reduce the effect
in the length picture.
Then switch to the curve direction.
After adjusting the parameters,
click on the application and turn on the rendering.
You can see that
the current effect
is different from the previous one.
In the hair vinegar generator,
the length picture also includes the cut picture.
After inserting the picture,
click on the application again
and turn on the rendering.
You can see that
the hair looks like a flower on the cut picture.
In addition,
we also provide you with
15 common hair materials
with hair vinegar effect.
About the content of the hair vinegar generator,
we will explain in detail
in a video later.
If you are interested,
remember to pay attention.
Next,
we will add a new color to the handbag.
When we click on the default way to add,
the mouse will appear
when the material,
all properties,
and linkage are close to each other,
and the corresponding frame will appear
to explain the added color properties
of the material and linkage.
In the new version,
you can directly drag the material
from the handbag window,
the object window,
or the local folder
to the color editor window
to change the color more conveniently.
Now we drag a material
directly from the handbag window
and release the mouse
on the material information frame
that we want to change.
For the material in the object window,
when you drag the added material
from the object window
to the 3D clothing,
you can see that
there is a link
that applies to the color.
In the window,
you can specify how to apply the material
to the color in the default situation.
You can choose only to apply to the current color
or apply to all colors
and choose material or linkage.
After you set the default settings
and click OK,
this window will not appear again.
When you drag the material
from the object window
to the 3D clothing,
you can see that
there is a prompt icon
on the mouse.
You can use the control key
to switch the color application
and quickly choose the color effect
you want to use.
In the new version of the color,
you can also hide multiple stickers.
First, we add a sticker to the handbag
and adjust the Z-axis distance
of the sticker to show the sticker.
In the new version of the Z-axis distance,
you can use the control key
to select the color of the sticker
that does not need to be hidden.
Right-click to hide other stickers,
then other stickers
other than the color
will be hidden.
Next,
we open the shirt group file
that has already worn the handbag
and adjust the model information display
to the grid surface.
Click on the model
to adjust the model grid
level.
The higher the level,
the more grid the model has.
The smoother the skin,
the better the display effect
of wearing tight clothing.
In 2024.2,
the conflict processing ability of
the GPU simulation has been improved.
First, we can see that
the CPU and GPU can be switched
in the simulation mode.
Then, you can choose
the most common mode
to do the demonstration.
We add a chest coat
to do the matching of clothing.
After opening the simulation,
you will find that
the conflict processing of
the current GPU simulation
is very good.
We can also rotate
to different angles
to see the result.
Generally speaking,
compared to the CPU simulation,
the speed of the GPU simulation
will be faster.
Now you see the left window
and the right window
are GPU simulation and CPU simulation.
Apply a pose to this suit.
You can see that
the speed of the CPU simulation
and GPU simulation is faster.
Finally,
the window ring design also
changes.
In 2024.2,
we can achieve a more stable
and portable copy simulation.
Right-click the button to close the loop,
you can see the added copy simulation.
Open the simulation,
use your hand to capture the copy.
You can see the interaction between
the copy and the template.
The copy will not easily penetrate the template.
The simulation is more stable.
Finally, we make a rendering output for this whole set of clothes, open the rendering window, picture, video properties, and switch to all colors in the color selection, and save a column at the bottom to add a new one.
So that in the final rendering, you will get a single picture with multiple colors and all colors.
After 3D design is complete, you can upload the file to Closet.
In Closet, there are two main functions released this season.
One is the new content paragraph management tool, which allows you to record clothing information in detail.
Enter the content page, click the arrow button on the left to display detailed information.
You can fill in every paragraph here.
You can also customize the paragraph according to the type of file, such as Closet project, fabric, and so on.
By using the new content paragraph tool, you can share file information more efficiently.
The other is the new configuration tool.
By using the new tool, you can regularly edit the material properties of 3D clothing online.
On the right side of the 3D viewfinder, click the new configuration button.
You can regularly edit the material properties.
You can change the color, such as use Pantone, ColorRow color.
You can also add text and PBR stickers.
You can also adjust the text ratio and position by editing text tools.
The new color scheme can be downloaded back to Closet for further editing.
Through the new configuration tool, non-Closet users can also participate in design and development and try new color schemes together.
The main functions of this update are introduced here.
Which new function impressed you the most?
In the future, we will further introduce the function summary video with key functions.
Please continue to pay attention to the content of the official account.
Welcome to leave your opinion or practical experience in the comments area.
Closet's progress is inseparable from your attention and feedback.
See you next time.